<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>markets on goodalexander</title>
    <link>https://goodalexander.github.io/tags/markets/</link>
    <description>Recent content in markets on goodalexander</description>
    <image>
      <title>goodalexander</title>
      <url>https://goodalexander.github.io/papermod-cover.png</url>
      <link>https://goodalexander.github.io/papermod-cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 11:21:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://goodalexander.github.io/tags/markets/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What Do Markets Mean to Me</title>
      <link>https://goodalexander.github.io/posts/investment-philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 11:21:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://goodalexander.github.io/posts/investment-philosophy/</guid>
      <description>My Investment Philosophy as Best as I can explain. dfuq do I actually do
A lot of people think I’m “insane” or “on drugs”, per Twitter discourse .I want to explain what I do for a living and how it all fits together.
Everything Is Rigged First - I believe the market is rigged. There isn’t a printer that goes brr. Central Banks buy assets - bonds, and sometimes ETFs. Credit instruments and equities sensitive to credit rates get influenced by the daily actions of central banks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Left Curve Path</title>
      <link>https://goodalexander.github.io/posts/left-curve-path/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 11:21:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://goodalexander.github.io/posts/left-curve-path/</guid>
      <description>AI Good. Fiat Bad. What&amp;rsquo;s your plan, anon?
What Is The Left Curve Most internet denizens know this meme by now&amp;hellip; but, for reference
It pays to keep it really simple.
The Morpheus Bull A crypto bull market is arriving. It’s time to dial down the spiritual thought, the hobbies, the relationships. The meditations on what it means to be human. And focus on making money.
Because the nature of money is changing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Simplistic Manifesto</title>
      <link>https://goodalexander.github.io/posts/simplistic-manifesto/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 11:21:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://goodalexander.github.io/posts/simplistic-manifesto/</guid>
      <description>Why am I doing what I am doing? A direct summary of all the esoteric garbage I&amp;rsquo;ve produced.
Dumbing it all down I’ve written a lot on this blog. I want to dumb it down. Speak in 10th grade English. Below I’m going to talk about what I think the dominant life strategy is, and why. Basically - it’s trying to make as much money as possible, at the intersection of crypto AI and capital markets, while living in Puerto Rico.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Mo</title>
      <link>https://goodalexander.github.io/posts/the-mo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 11:21:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://goodalexander.github.io/posts/the-mo/</guid>
      <description>channeling momentum, mojo, reading the universal mosaic
Below I explore the idea of “the Mo” - or being in tune with the universe, in a useful way that allows you to take larger risks and do better work - but only in short bursts.
Famous fund manager Stanley Druckenmiller has stated that the most fundamental job of a trader is knowing whether or not he has a “hot hand”. When you have a hot hand, you size up.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asylum Sidepots. How to Escape the Matrix and Stay Out</title>
      <link>https://goodalexander.github.io/posts/asylum-sidepots/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 11:21:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://goodalexander.github.io/posts/asylum-sidepots/</guid>
      <description>Escaping the socio-spiritual prison from the starting position of a speculator
Sidepots in the Asylum When I started trading, I was in it for money and pride. My father lost a lot of money starting a hedge fund and we lost our house when I was a kid. I got into trading as some kind of redemption arc.
My father is a renegade. He viewed markets as a way to escape the simulation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Vision of the Future</title>
      <link>https://goodalexander.github.io/posts/vision-of-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 11:21:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://goodalexander.github.io/posts/vision-of-future/</guid>
      <description>A hypothetical exploration of the world we are heading towards
There have been 3 major technology shifts since 2022. The market has weighted one much higher in terms of valuation - Artificial Intelligence. But a second, more subtle shift was the launch of the MetaQuest Pro and improvement of visual tracking in Virtual Reality. A third, and final tech change is the rise of ZK technology in cryptocurrency enabling highly scalable, verifiable and largely anonymous currency transactions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Withering Trader’s Illustrated Primer</title>
      <link>https://goodalexander.github.io/posts/withering-trader-primer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2023 11:21:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://goodalexander.github.io/posts/withering-trader-primer/</guid>
      <description>the Last Samurai, Darth Vader, the world of entertainment bleeding into the world of things
“There are only two industries. This has always been true&amp;hellip;.There is the industry of things, and the industry of entertainment&amp;hellip;.After people have the things they need to live, everything else is entertainment. Everything.” ― Neal Stephenson, The Diamond Age: Or, a Young Lady&amp;rsquo;s Illustrated Primer
Now that I’ve spent some more time in the weeds with LLMs as applied to capital markets, I have some reflections about what the building blocks are, how things are likely to play out as well as how I’m going to position myself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retrofixation</title>
      <link>https://goodalexander.github.io/posts/retrofixation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 11:21:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://goodalexander.github.io/posts/retrofixation/</guid>
      <description>naming negative nostalgia. exploring clarity in a world with infinite RAM
Naming the Culprit A single concept applies to bad investing, bad decision making, and bad feelings. The idea is living in the past.
I began exploring this concept by speaking to my friend Kyla about nostalgia, and its role in Brexit, the election of Donald Trump, guys who only eat meat, luddite behavior, and economic desperation. She recorded a video about it here</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cracks in the Fishbowl </title>
      <link>https://goodalexander.github.io/posts/cracks-in-the-fishbowl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 18:21:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://goodalexander.github.io/posts/cracks-in-the-fishbowl/</guid>
      <description>a reflection on Nietzsche, Artificial Intelligence, goldfish, and new Gods
“God is dead. God remains dead. And we have killed him. How shall we comfort ourselves, the murderers of all murderers? What was the holiest and mightiest of all that the world has yet owned has bled to death under our knives: who will wipe this blood off us? Is not the greatness of this deed too great for us? Must we ourselves not become gods simply to appear worthy of it?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 2 - Decline and Fall</title>
      <link>https://goodalexander.github.io/posts/letsgo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 18:21:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://goodalexander.github.io/posts/letsgo/</guid>
      <description>Ideas expressing weakness in US equities relative to ROW this week
Last Week Last week&amp;rsquo;s performance was +1.25%, unlevered had you traded this blog post on the open Monday and held til Friday Source: Last Week&amp;rsquo;s Write Up . Full breakdown at a trade level here. Download
Big tech and the virus acceleration were separated from the political narrative. I think it is notable that the basket titled &amp;ldquo;Green Old Deal&amp;rdquo; was the top performer, with big up moves in Uranium stocks throughout the week.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tokyo Swerve- Careful What You Wish For</title>
      <link>https://goodalexander.github.io/posts/tokyo-swerve/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 11:21:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://goodalexander.github.io/posts/tokyo-swerve/</guid>
      <description>extreme FX and interest rate volatility paints a picture of 2 very different worlds. which shall we step into?
Let&amp;rsquo;s start with a question. If Japan has rock bottom risk-free rates, shouldn&amp;rsquo;t its companies command higher multiples? Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t Japan be a global hub of innovation - because low rates and structural deflation allow for investment in growth?
To the first question - Japanese companies certainly do not command higher multiples. Japan&amp;rsquo;s TOPIX Index has a forward PE ratio is 12, while it has a 30-year bond yield of 1.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Postulates on Useful Financial Speech</title>
      <link>https://goodalexander.github.io/posts/postulates-on-financial-speech/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 11:21:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://goodalexander.github.io/posts/postulates-on-financial-speech/</guid>
      <description>Previously I wrote about the evolution of media and how it ends in a poorly defined digital Colosseum. Here I write in detail about how/ why that Colosseum will entail the creation of financial eSports
Financial markets are unique from politics, science, or other arenas of the media because they are accompanied by Timeseries. For the most part these timeseries consist of a price which implies a value (i.e. what you&amp;rsquo;re paying the price for) and an expectation (what that price implies - relative to historical prices, relevant comparables, consensus values and so forth).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stepping into Phase Seven</title>
      <link>https://goodalexander.github.io/posts/entering-phase-seven/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 11:21:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://goodalexander.github.io/posts/entering-phase-seven/</guid>
      <description>one last musing before the descent into the digital colosseum
Digital assets and the political media have wrapped around each other, a double helix of increasingly epic proportions. It has not always been like this, but a glimpse of where we are today, before discussing the portal that’s opened behind my casomputer chair that I am about to step through -
Central bankers posting their thoughts on the daily to the derision of random armchair Austrian economists on the internet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Discussion on the Study of Asset Price Movement</title>
      <link>https://goodalexander.github.io/posts/discussion-on-asset-price-movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 11:21:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://goodalexander.github.io/posts/discussion-on-asset-price-movement/</guid>
      <description>A 35 point summary of how I define speculation, its 6 core components and thoughts around implementation
Investors are not traders. Investors focus on the capital return potential of assets, adjusted for a discount rate. Traders focus on capturing the movement of assets. An investor may trade, to swap into a more appealing capital return or asset. But a trader would rarely invest - as that would suppose capital returns made up a higher percentage of an asset’s return profile than its movement.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Absurdity Supercycle- Being Early After the End of History</title>
      <link>https://goodalexander.github.io/posts/absurdity-supercycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 11:21:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://goodalexander.github.io/posts/absurdity-supercycle/</guid>
      <description>reflections on recent price action, ARK investments, Palantir, and crypto</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Common Stocks and Uncommon Profits</title>
      <link>https://goodalexander.github.io/posts/common-stocks-uncommon-profits/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 18:25:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://goodalexander.github.io/posts/common-stocks-uncommon-profits/</guid>
      <description>Common Stocks and Uncommon Profits gets frequently recommended to me by top performing equity managers. It&amp;rsquo;s 15 rules for evaluating growth stocks. I read it and summarized it.
Summary Rote changes in revenue and earnings are less interesting than their quality and repeatability. Invest in a company with capable, honest and adaptive management entering an under penetrated market that invests its resources in such a way to give it optionality into new spaces.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
